Zoë McDaniel

\$ 804.298.9515 @ zmcdaniel@gmail.com % https://zoemcdaniel.com ♥ Seattle, WA

SUMMARY

I'm a full-stack, front-leaning web developer with a passion for building thoughtful interactions between people and objects. My diverse experiences ranging from code to customer satisfaction to carpentry make me a creative problem solver who continuously strives to improve my skills and knowledge.

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

General Assembly 2016 - ongoing Seattle, WA

As a full-stack developer, I created scalable products in stacks including Ruby on Rails & MEAN. I bolstered skills in development as well as collaborative teamwork to develop, maintain, and secure web applications

- Built and deployed four project web apps with normalized databases, MVC organization, RESTful routes, & DRY coding concepts
- Planned applications from the ground up, including wireframes, features, code organization, & database tables, prioritizing accordingly to deliver fully functioning projects in less than 5 days

Front of House

Huxley Wallace Collective Mar 2016 - July 2016 Seattle, WA

Restaurant group developing beautiful spaces, food experiences & creative ventures. I specialized in high-volume full service at their stadium-side venue.

- Served, bussed, hosted, & bartended with sales exceeding \$4,000 daily
- Personally hosted high-profile guest including Seahawks' Richard Sherman, Mariners' Robinson Cano, & US National Women's Soccer Team

Front of House

Jack's BBQ May 2015 - May 2016 Seattle, WA

Winner, Best BBQ in Seattle. I was consistently recognized for high sales, customer rapport, repeat visitors, and my hands-on approach to learning the fine art, history, and techniques of Central Texas BBQ

- Mastered every FOH position & coordinated catering for events including weddings, corporate lunches, & the Seattle Met 20th Anniversary Gala
- Published marketing materials and ran campaigns promoting events such as exclusive dinners, weekly specials, & seasonal menu changes

Assistant Manager

Rainin' Ribs Smokehouse Nov 2014 - May 2015 Seattle, WA

Managed front-of-house employees and duties

- Processed catering orders and maintained client relationships
- Designed & published a weekly newsletter with a 20% open rate, managed/updated social media, and maintained company website

Web Developer

True North LLC Apr 2013 - Dec 2015 Virginia Beach, VA

At this small general contracting company, I was both a historical preservation contractor as well as a web developer

- Developed and managed regularly updated company website and portfolio. eventually migrating it to WordPress
- Renovated, painted, and restored 18th-19th century buildings and homes

PROJECTS

Mind Dump

A freeform journaling and mindfulness application that provides linguistic tone analysis

- Sole designer and developer
- Leveraged IBM machine learning technology

Accio Bike

Developer, designer, & manager for Ruby on Rails app for prevention & recovery from bicycle theft

- Project manager for team of four
- Completed project in a one-week sprint

Gem Jam

Designed & developed retro-inspired platformer game using the Phaser.io Javascript engine

- Hand-created custom spritesheet
- Completed project in a 5-day sprint

TECHNOLOGIES

Languages

Javascript Python Ruby Java

Web Frameworks



Software



EDUCATION

Computer Science

University of San Francisco 2011 - 2013 San Francisco, CA

Web Development **Immersive**

General Assembly

2016 Seattle, WA